JAMIE WATERS



jamierwaters@pm.me



07703395492



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamiewaters-450a021b5/

Currently Studying at Guildhall School of Music and Drama – Theatre Technology

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

A-LEVELS

Chemistry - A

Biology - A

Physics – A

EPQ - A*

GCSES

Eight 9s, One 8, Two 7s

First Aid at Work – Valid to Nov 2024

Dante Certification Level 3 – Achieved Feb 2024

Enhanced DBS – Obtained 31st January 2023

Full UK Driving License – Cat B,

KEY SKILLS

ETC Eos

Dante Networking

Q-Lab

dLive

X32

Yamaha CL Series

Project Management

Health and Safety

PROFILE

Jamie is a Freelance AV and Theatre Technician with a focus on live sound. Jamie has 8 years of technical experience, including a year of professional work. He appreciates the creative problem solving involved in technical theatre and especially theatrical sound. He has worked on a range of shows and events from supervising sound at Ed fringe 2024 to a small-scale tour with NTW in late 2023. He is passionate about how immersive and semi-immersive theatre can involve the audience in experiencing a deeper connection to the story.

EXPERIENCE

AREA 2 SOUND SUPERVISOR, THE PLEASANCE EDINBRUGH FRINGE 2024 07/2024-08/2024

Looking after the medium sized venues from a Sound/Video perspective throughout the festival proividing first line support to the venue crews to ensure smooth running of the festival based at the Pleasance Courtyard.

AUDIO VISAUAL TECHNICIAN (SOUND BIAS), TAG LIVE, SEAL BAY RESORT 02/2024 – 04/2024

Working as part of a small team of 6 technicians responsible for supporting the park wide entertainment package, this involves stage duties, operating winch, mixing light entertainment bands and cast shows as well as firing pyro. Furthermore, we deliver constant improvements to the systems and shows for example by installing new kit such as new pyro pods and fitting sparkulars. The job also involves a large amount of Qlab work which has developed my experience in Qlab's Video offering.

SOUND AND VIDEO TECHNICIAN, CIRCLE OF FIFTHS, NATIONAL THEATRE FOR WALES 02/10/2023 – 14/11/2023

Responsible for the Sound and Video aspects of the show while on tour, as well as responsible for Sound through the rehearsal process.

FREELANCE SOUND/AV TECHNICIAN

07/2023 - Present

Taking on a variety of roles in Corporate AV settings from Lighting Operation to A2.

STUDENT TECHNICIAN, UNIVERSITY OF YORK AUDIO VISUAL DEPARTMENT 06/2023 – 09/2023

A varied, paid role involving both maintaining and testing teaching equipment (Extron/Crestron), as well as providing technical services for larger events across campus such as external conferences (e.g., AFPP, General Synod).

EQUIPMENT AND HIRES MANAGER, UNIVERSITY OF YORK TECHNICAL THEATRE SOCIETY

03/2023 - 06/2023

Responsible for the storage and maintenance of the societies technical equipment worth £175 000, as well as leading a small team to help Prep and De-prep for events. I was also responsible for creating and updating the societies RAMS, documentation, and booking additional hires.

TECHNICAL MANAGER, UNIVERSITY OF YORK DRAMA SOCIETY 01/2023 - Present

A voluntary committee position responsible for maintaining the Drama Barn's (the society's dedicated performance space) kit and equipment. Additional responsibilities include teaching members how to use the equipment (ETC Eos/Qlab) and helping shows rig and derig. Part of the role was also to provide technical guidance where required.

DIRECTOR – TETRA BIO DISTRIBUTED

07/2020 - Present

During the Covid-19 Pandemic I lead a project with a group of engineers from around the world to design a ventilator splitter that enabled one ventilator to be shared by up to 4 people. This was an interesting project to lead as it involved coordinating and managing a diverse group of people and locations, as well as the challenges of designing a product while no one could meet in person.

ADDITIONAL SHOW CREDITS

LIGHTING DESIGNER – MOJO, UNIVERSITY OF YORK DRAMA SOCIETY, 28/11-03/12/2023

STAGE MANAGER - SPETCHLY THROUGH THE WARDROBE, ALI CHAMBERS CREATIVE EVENTS 30/10 - 02/11/2023

SOUND DESIGNER AND OPERATOR – GILBERT AND SULLIVAN SUMMER SHOW, UNIVERSITY OF YORK GILBERT AND SULLIVAN SOCIETY, 07/2023

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR - THE ADDAMS FAMILY, CENTRAL HALL MUSICAL SOCIETY, 04-06/2023

PROJECT MANAGER (ATHLETICS TRACK) - ROSES 2023, YORK VS LANCASTER VARSITY, 04/2023

ASSISTANT PROJECT MANAGER - LITTLE SHOP OF HORRORS, CENTRAL HALL MUSICAL SOCIETY, 03/2023

LIGHTING DESIGNER - THE UNSPOKEN, UNIVERSITY OF YORK DRAMA SOCIETY, 02 - 03/2023

SOUND 2 – SUNSHINE ON LEITH, CENTRAL HALL MUSICAL SOCIETY, 02/2023

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR – JULIUS CAESAR, UNIVERSITY OF YORK SHAKESPEARE SOCIETY, 01 – 02/2023

SOUND OPERATOR – AUTUMN SOIREE 2022, CENTRAL HALL MUSICAL SOCIETY, 10/2022

LIGHTING AND SOUND DESIGNER - LEFT BEHIND, UNIVERSITY OF YORK DRAMA SOCIETY, 11/2022

LIGHTING DESIGNER – BLUE STOCKINGS, UNIVERSITY OF YORK DRAMA SOCIETY, 11/2022

TECHNICAL ASSISTANT - GRIMMS TALES, KINGS SCHOOL WORCESTER, 02/2022

SOUND I - WE WILL ROCK YOU, KINGS SCHOOL WORCESTER, 12/2021

ASSISTANT SOUND OPERATOR - MADE IN DAGENHAM, KINGS SCHOOL WORCESTER, 12/2019